

David Munoz-Tord Data Scientist

Contact

Geneva, Switzerland

+41 79 244 1756

david.munoztord@mailbox.org

david-munoztord.com

munozt0

Skills

R	9 yrs.
Python	5 yrs.
JavaScript	3 yrs.
Bash	7 yr.
SQL	4 yrs.
Matlab	4 yr.
Data Analysis	9 years
Data Engineering	5 yrs.
Web Development	4 years

Summary

Data Scientist with 9 years of experience in the analysis of all sorts of data. I have a strong background in hierarchical modeling and I am an expert in R. I am passionate about Open Science and I am experienced in building and maintaining open source projects. I am a team player and I have experience in leading and coordinating projects.

Experience

Freelancer - Data Scientist

10/2022 - Present

EPFL Collaboration

Led the development and launch of a scientific project, transitioned scripts into a SaaS solution, and offered technical consulting services to startups in cognitive technologies.

FlowBank - Full Stack Data Scientist

01/2023 - 01/2024

FlowBank

Analyzed customer data using Bayesian inference, designed ETL workflows, and developed internal tools for data analysts.

FlowBank - R Developer/Data Engineer

04/2022 - 01/2023

FlowBank

Implemented statistical models to detect fraudulent transactions, designed data visualization dashboards, and led the development of data science infrastructure.

University of Geneva - Lecturer in Statistics

09/2020 - 01/2022

Master of Neurosciences program

Conducted statistics lectures, developed course materials, mentored graduate students, and shared data workshops in R and Python.

Projects

See my github profile for a comprehensive list of open source projects.

R packages

Creator and Maintainer

edgebundle, graphlayouts, levelnet, netrankr, netUtils, networkdata, PSAWR, roughnet, roughsf, rtoot, Rtumblr, signnet, snahelper, webbotparseR, webtrackR

R packages

Contributor

backbone, ggraph, multigraphr, netropy, rang, rgraph6

Quarto extensions

Creator and Maintainer

Academicons (shortcodes), Blackboard (revealjs theme), sketchy (html theme), share buttons (filter), nutshell (filter), quartocities (website template), quartocv (cv templates)

Frameworks

- R Shiny
- TensorFlow
- Keras
- PyTorch
- Rstan
- Scikit-learn
- tidymodels

Tools/Paradigms

- ▶ Git
- Terminal
- Docker
- ▶ CI/CD
- AWS
- ML OPS
- ▶ ETL

Education

03/2020 - 01/2022

Ph.D. Candidate in Computal Neuroscience

University of Geneva

Topic: Computational modeling of addiction using neuroimaging data

09/2018 - 03/2020

MSc in Neuroscience

University of Geneva

Thesis: Denoising of high resolution fMRI signal using tICA

09/2017 - 06/2018

Complementary Studies in Computer Science

Smith College

Capstone: Machine Learning for neuroimaging data

09/2014 - 06/2017

soccerverse.com (football analytics website)

Creator and Maintainer

Manual and automated gathering of football results around the world, Harmonizing data (e.g. club names and managers), Implementation of ranking algorithms, Predicting of league tables and matchforecasting, Uses R, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, around 1000 visitors/month

BSc in Cognitive Science

University of Geneva

Thesis: Early detection of ASD